Partial Inventoryof the Richard Wormser Interviews
Hoover Institution Archives
Richard Wormser interviews
1980-1981
2010C36
Wormser, Richard, interviewer
9 manuscript boxes (3.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Video recordings of interviews of leaders and associates of the Communist Party of the United States of America, relating to communism in the United States.
Administrative Information
Access
Closed until 2014 July 1.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2010.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Video recordings of interviews of leaders and associates of the Communist Party of the United States of America, relating to communism in the United States.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Communism--United States; Communist Party of the United States of America; Videotapes
Collection Contents
- Video recordings of interviews, 1980-1986 (Box 1-7)
  - Video recording of interview of Malcolm Cowley, undated; U-matic videocassettes 2-5 (there is no videocassette 1). Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004110 (Box 1)
  - Video recording of interview of Sam Darcy, 12 April 1981; U-matic videocassettes 3-4 (box 2), videocassette 1 (box 8), videocassette 2 (box 9). Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004111 (Box 2, 8, 9)
  - Video recording of interview of Gil Green, 11 April 1981; U-matic videocassettes 4-6 (box 3), videocassette 2 (box 8); videocassette 3 (box 9). Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004113 (Box 2, 8, 9)
  - Video recording of interview of Gus Hall, 15 April 1981; U-matic videocassettes 1-3. Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004115 (Box 4)
  - Video recording of interview of John Hammond, 16 April 1981; U-matic videocassettes 1-2. Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004120 (Box 4)
  - Video recording of interview of John Houseman, 5 June 1986; Appears to be a film to tape transfer. 1 U-matic videocassette. Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004122 (Box 4)
  - Video recording of interview of Clarence Norris, 1981; U-matic videocassettes 1-2. Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004123 (Box 5)
  - Video recording of interview of Steve Nelson, 19 May 1981; U-matic videocassette 3 (box 5), videocassette 1 (box 9), videocassette 2 (box 8). Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004126 (Box 5, 8, 9)
  - Video recording of interview of Edna Ocko, 9 April 1981; U-matic videocassettes 1-3. Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004127 (Box 5)
  - Video recording of interview of Anne Timpson, 11 April 1981; U-matic videocassette 2 (there is no videocassette 1). Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004130 (Box 6)
  - Video recording of interview of Will Weinstone, 14 April 1981; U-matic videocassettes 1-2. Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004131 (Box 6)
  - Video recording of interview of Edith Segal, 9 April 1981; U-matic videocassettes 2-3 (there is no videocassette 1). Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004132 (Box 6)
  - Video recording of interview of Max Gordon, Max Weiss and Sid Stein, 9 April 1981; U-matic videocassette 1 (box 6), videocassettes 2, 4 (box 8), videocassette 3 (box 9). Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004133 (Box 6, 8, 9)
  - Video recording of interview of Henry Winston, 15 April 1981; U-matic videocassettes 1-2, 4 (box 7), videocassette 3 (box 4). Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0004135 (Box 4, 7)
  - Video recording of interview of Pete Seeger, undated; There are no preservation master videotapes; rather there is one DVD that has been deemed a duplication copy, from which a DVD access copy was made. Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0007382
  - Video recording of interview of Robert (Bob) Schrank, undated; There are no preservation master videotapes; rather there are 3 DVDs that have been deemed a duplication copy, from which DVD access copies were made. Use copy reference number: 2010c36_v_0007384